轻点打字 混蛋
Type quieter, asshole.
提前收工 大家都撤
Early relief. So get the fuck out of here.
老天 Bunk 几点了
Jesus, Bunk. What time is it?
四点半
4:30.
我睡不着 还是收工算了
I couldn't sleep, so get the fuck gone.
McNulty昨晚几点走的
What time did McNulty leave last night?
没走 他在1号审讯室
Never did. He's in number one.
不晓得绞尽脑汁的捣鼓些啥
Pulling his hair out over some shit.
你最好搞清楚自己在干嘛
Think again about what the fuck you're doing.
Bunk 这么做可行
Bunk, this can work.
肯定可行
It can.
滚你妈的 没开玩笑
Fuck you. I mean that.
Jimmy 这才早上四点
Jimmy, four in the fuckin' morning?
那又怎样
So it is.
所有这些?
All of these?
都是过去五年发生的流浪汉谋杀案
Homeless murders from the last five years.
旧事就算作古了  但这些案子足矣
Everything before that is on microfilm, but we got enough right here.
- Jimmy - 大部分都没结案
- Jimmy. - Most of it open.
我们在流浪汉谋杀这块一直做得不咋地
We don't do so well with homeless killings.
他们颠沛流离 没亲人没朋友 没人管他们死活
Transient locales, no nearest,  no dearest.No one gives a fuck.
都是些永远结不了的案子
Cases stay open forever.
你搞这些就等着坐牢 坐定了
You're going to jail behind this shit. Yes, you are.
知道监狱里的警察是什么下场? 尤其是像你这种靓仔?
You know what they do to police in jail? Pretty police like yourself?
你他妈的 我们还有孩子
Motherfucker, we have kids.
还有房子 车贷 家具
Houses. Car payments. Furniture.
Jimmy 我才买了崭新草坪椅 和庭院玻璃茶几
Jimmy, I just bought brand-new lawn chairs and a glass patio table.
要是准备被炒鱿鱼和抓去坐牢 还买这些操蛋玩意儿作甚
Now, you don't buy no shit like that if you planning to lose your job and go to prison.
你连法医那关都蒙不过去
You won't even get past the ME.
- 等着瞧 - 你把这些未了公案丢给我们
- Watch me. - You're dumping murders on us
破又破不了  破案率会下降得很难看
that we can't solve, you're fucking the squad's clearance rate.
去他的破案率
Fuck the fucking numbers already.
该死的数字毁了这该死的警局
The fucking numbers destroyed this fucking department.
Landsman和他的破案率都吃屎去吧
Landsman and his clearance rate can suck a hairy asshole.
- Marlo不值得你这么做 哥们 不值 - Marlo是个人渣
- Marlo ain't worth it, man. Nobody is. - Marlo's an asshole.
不能让他就这么赢 赢的该是我们
He does not get to win. We get to win.
上头不拨款案件又不会凭空消失
This case doesn't go away just because the bosses can't find the money to pay for it.
这些可都是谋杀啊-
These are fucking murders -
贫民区谋杀 但还是一样
ghetto murders, but still,
我从西区调回来就是为了这件案子
I came back out of the Western to work this case
因为他们信誓旦旦说此案必结
because they said it would be worked.
我为了这句承诺才回来 休想给我开空头支票
I came back out on a promise, and they're gonna keep that promise.
不管是明着来还是瞒着来
Whether they know it or not.
我会告诉Landsman
I'm gonna tell Landsman.
你这样执迷不悟 我不能帮你隐瞒
Yeah. You keep on with it, I'm gonna rat you out.
随你便
Well, you do what you got to do.
我的名字绝对不能出现在文件里
My name is nowhere in the file.
我不想跟这件事扯上任何关系
I don't want fuck to do with this.
喂 Bunk
Hey, Bunk.
* When you walk through the garden *
火线重案组 第五季 第3集
the.wire.s05e03
* you gotta watch your back *
* well I beg your pardon *
* walk the straight and narrow track *
* if you walk with Jesus *
* he's gonna save your soul *
* you gotta keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* he's got the fire and the fury *
* at his command *
* well you don't have to worry *
* if you hold on to Jesus hand *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* when the thunder rolls *
* just gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
他们没死在对的地方 -Fletcher
- 你干嘛去 - 报纸出了
- What are you doing? - Final is out.
我要看我的报道
I want to see my story.
- 现在 - 这是我第一次实地报道
- Now? - It's my first time out front.
- 我想看成果 - 这就是为什么我们该订报送上门
- I want to see it. - This is why we should get home delivery.
能从办公室拿免费的干嘛还要付钱
Why pay for it when I get it for free at the office?
去去就回
Be back.
Ray老兄
Brother Ray.
愿你安息
God rest ye.
太阳报什么时候到货
When does the Sun get here?
平常差不多就这时候
Around now usually.
西区发生入室行凶案件三人身亡
谁有可出动的警车
Anybody got a working car?
我有 但我要开回案发现场彻查
I got one, but I'm going back out to my crime scene for a canvass.
捎我去法医那里
Drop me at the ME?
Jimmy
Jimmy.
来我办公室 现在
My office, now.
我搭总部的车就行
I'll get a lift over from one of the central cars.
这比你以前做的操蛋事还出格得多 Jimmy 好好想清楚
This is way past any shit you ever pulled in your life, Jimmy. Think on it.
你也看见Greggs是怎样独自艰难取证
You see Greggs out there, bagging evidence alone,
还要去三尸案现场重新搜查
then going back out to recanvass on a triple?
他妈的三重谋杀
A triple fucking murder,
入室行凶 还只有她一人调查
a home invasion, and she's working it alone.
上头把Crutchfield调出来了 让他回去轮班
They pulled Crutchfield this morning, put him back in the rotation.
- 那错在他们 但你不能... - 当然错在他们
- That's on them, but you can't... - Fucking right, that's on them.
三重谋杀案  12小时之后他们竟只留一位警探调查
A triple murder, and 12 hours later they leave one detective alone on it?
她有辆车还算她走运
I guess she's lucky she has a car.
- 这么做绝对不是办法 - 再差也不会比以前糟到哪儿去
- This shit won't work. - Then we're no worse than before.
- 不过在板上多出一两个未结案的名字罢了 - 除非你被人抓住
- Extra red name or two on the board. - Yeah, unless you got caught.
组里谁会抓得住我
Who in this fucking unit is gonna catch me?
这里大部分人上墨西哥妓院 连个淋病都染不上
Most of the guys up here couldn't catch the clap in a Mexican whorehouse.
红丝带是怎么回事
What's with the red ribbon?
Barlow几年前有起没结的勒杀案
Barlow had an open strangle a few years back.
被勒死的流浪汉手上系着红丝带
Homeless guy with a red ribbon tied around his wrist.
这么一来就有两起
So that's two.
还有 我从Ray Cole的旧案里 翻出一起流浪汉案件
Also, I found an open homeless case which Ray Cole worked.
我把红丝带写进他的案报里
I wrote a ribbon into his office reports.
- 这样就有三起 - 我们手头那个尸体可没有红丝带
- So there's three. - Our guy didn't have a red ribbon.
- 我这就去 - 老天 听你自己在说什么
- That's where I'm headed. - Jesus. Listen to yourself.
当官的根本不管真正的连环杀人犯
Upstairs wouldn't jump on a real serial killer -
Marlo这混蛋 杀人如麻
fuckin' Marlo, who's got bodies all over him.
也许上头需要这些假象才会重视
Well, maybe they need the make-believe.
我看你才是精神错乱的混蛋
Yeah, maybe you're the asshole just lost his fucking mind.
- 我被锁在审讯室里了 - 审讯室?
- Yeah, I'm locked in the box. - In the box?
- 这不好笑 让我出去 - 马上来
- It's no joke. Let me out. - Be right there.
Jimmy
Jimmy.
他搞你了?
He fuck you?
他想来着
He tried...
但总的来说他是想搞死自己
but mostly he just fucks himself.
你还没看过这些 对吧
You ain't seen those yet, huh?
你肯定没有
I'll bet you didn't.
Burrell这家伙还真倔
Fucking Burrell's asshole must be so tight
简直用约翰迪尔拖拉机都拉不回来
you couldn't pull a pin from it with a John Deere tractor.
这边你承诺要把犯罪率降低两位数
Here you're promising a double-digit drop,
他竟然连续两季给你增加4%
and he gives you a 4% bump for two quarters in a row.
- 谢谢你告诉我这个 - 我好心给你提个醒
- Thanks for bringing these by, Stan. - I wanted to give you a heads-up.
事实上 看到这样惨不忍睹的数据
Truth is, looking at numbers like those,
我觉得你还不如
I'm thinking you could do a lot worse
让我当代理局长试试
than give me a run as acting commissioner.
我知道你不能让我一直当下去
I know you couldn't make me permanent,
也许让我作六个月  在此期间栽培你的Daniels
maybe six months while you keep grooming your boy Daniels.
我能拿到更多退休金
I'd get a pension bump,
你终于可以开始清理门户
and you'd get a head start on clearing out deadwood,
就从Burrell和Rawls开始
beginning with Burrell and Rawls.
谢了 Stan
Thanks, Stan.
- 让我考虑下 - 你好好想清楚 Tommy
- Let me think on it. - You do that, Tommy.
就算只是在表演课上
Even on an acting basis, can you imagine
你能想象Nerese及幕僚们 怎么对付得了Valchek局长吗
Nerese and the ministers dealing  with Commissioner Valchek?
你准备怎么处理犯罪率的问题
What are you gonna do about the numbers?
我还能怎么做
Fuck can I do?
是我把警局预算削减到最低
I cut the department budget to the bone, right?
犯罪率上去了也无可厚非
Can't very well complain when the crime rate bumps.
Burrell如果来这儿 交出这种数据
Burrell comes in here and owns these,
我也只能放他一马  至少再也要先解决他们的资金问题
I got to give him a pass, at least until I can fix his money problems.
你的报道不走运呐
Your piece took a bad bite there.
版面从35寸缩水到12寸
35 inches down to 12?
这个嘛 没把它放到头版是我不对
Yeah, well, it's my fault for giving it up to the A-section.
头版编辑抱怨说会显得太突兀
Page-one editor made noises like it was gonna go out front
然后他在第三遍校对前把稿子 丢回给市内新闻版
and then he tossed it back to  Metro before the double-dot.
夜班编辑又没排出版面放这篇新闻 所以...
Night editor didn't have room to take it back, so...
这报道值得更大版面的 对不起
Story deserved better. Sorry.
三人在室内被谋杀
Three people murdered in a house,
就只有报纸下端区区12寸的篇幅
and it gets 12 inches below the fold.
给我解释一下
Explain that to me.
没什么好解释的
There's no explaining it.
广告收入少了 新闻版面更加受限
Advertising's down, we got a smaller news hole,
我们没处理好
we're not managing it well.
我们搞砸了
We messed up.
就这样
That's all.
邮编不对
Wrong zip code.
他们没死在对的地方
They're dead where it doesn't count.
如果死的是白人 而且是在Timonium被杀
If they were white and murdered in Timonium,
你30寸的头条就拿定了
you'd have had 30 inches off the front.
本该是我第一次单独署名的头版头条
Would have been my first front-pager where I didn't share a byline.
是吗
Yeah?
我为了第一时间拿到这份报纸 一路开到Covington港口的印刷厂
I drove down to the Port Covington plant this morning to get a copy.
你不是第一个这么做的
You ain't the first to do that.
那具现场的尸体到了吗
Our 10-7 on the floor yet?
正在俯拍正面
He's by the overhead camera.
我要取指纹 确认他的身份
I need to grab prints, get him ID'd.
你不想等到他的照片发布再确认? 保持手原样以便追查别的线索?
Don't you want to wait for the post, keep his hands clean for trace?
我得知道这受害者是谁  这是第一要务
I need to know who my victim is. That's the priority.
你先把早餐吃完吧 我可以慢慢等
Finish your breakfast.  I got plenty of time.
指甲下面好像没什么东西
There's nothing under the nails that I can see.
我觉得可以冒这个险先取指纹
I think we can risk prints.
不太对劲
Something's up.
各位 请聚过来
Please. Gather round.
Steve能找人带话给大厅对面的 特点新闻和体育新闻部吗
Steve, could someone get word across the hall to Features and Sports?
- 没问题 - 我希望大家都过来听
- Sure. - We want everyone on this.
怎么 我们又被收购了
What, did we get sold again?
先是洛杉矶时报把我们买下 然后又是纽约论坛报
First the LA Times buys us up, then the Tribune.
(是大鱼就钓起来 是小鱼就放回河里)
钓鱼法则
Law of the fish.
- 咱们不过是不起眼的小鱼 - 也许我们能赢个普利策新闻奖呢
- We're the minnow. - Maybe we won a Pulitzer.
普利策奖还有一周 现在才四月初
Pulitzers are still a week away. It just turned April.
看Whiting那慌张样
Look at Whiting's pants.
如果我们赢个普利策奖 执行总编还不跟飞机屁股似的
If we won a Pulitzer, the executive editor would be tumescent.
飞机屁股?
Tum-what?
说英语 我只是个警方新闻记者
Speak English. I'm just a police reporter.
飞机的屁股--尾巴翘上天
Tumescent. Engorged.
就这个意思
Exactly.
这年头报业不景气
It's a bad time for newspapers,
想必你们都知道
as you all know.
新闻版面越来越少
The news hole is shrinking as
因为广告投资一直递减
advertising dollars continue to decline.
我们的发行量也在减少
Our circulation numbers are also down
有各式各样的媒体在跟我们竞争
as we compete with a variety of media.
技术决定着传播手段
Technology is driving distribution,
而今网络成为新闻和评论的免费来源
and the internet is a free source of news and opinions.
在这新生代夹缝中为求生存
Seeking a balance in this new world,
我们必须做出艰难的选择
we're now faced with hard choices.
1924年我们在伦敦开立了首个境外分部
We opened our first foreign bureau in London in 1924.
太阳报的境外新闻报道自此让人引以为豪
The Sun's foreign coverage has been a source of pride ever since.
所以在此
So it is with
我深表遗憾的...
tremendous regret...
宣布芝加哥已决定
that I tell you that Chicago has made it clear that the bureaus
在北京 莫斯科
in Beijing, Moscow,
耶路撒冷 约翰尼斯堡 和伦敦
Jerusalem, Johannesburg, and London
的分部均将关闭
will all be shuttered.
余下的新闻编辑部
Elsewhere in the newsroom,
将会面临新一轮的收购
there will be a fresh round of buyouts.
芝加哥已向我们定下了明确的预算目标
Chicago has given us some specific budgetary targets
导致新闻部将不得不做出艰难的抉择
that will require some hard choices throughout the newsroom.
我们 简单来说
We are, quite simply,
必须尽量少花钱多做事
going to have to find ways to do more with less.
那么接下来交给Tom
So I guess I will turn this over to Tom,
他将向你们说明更详细的要求
who will get into the specifics.
我知道你们都是满腹疑团
I know some of you have questions.
给我点时间让我讲完话再发问
If you could hold them for me until after I've had a chance to speak.
把你的文件夹都收拾收拾
Pull your clip book together.
- 赶紧找个新东家吧 - 首先 芝加哥向我们发了
- Time to find a new home. - First, Chicago has sent us
一份备忘录 注明了你们当前的选择
a memo outlining options that are available to those of you...
主动脉本应有弹性
The aorta should have elasticity to it,
但这个已经完全硬化
but it's rock hard.
掐死他的人该多等一两个月
Whoever strangled him could've just waited a month or two more.
这老兄本来就命不久矣
This guy was on his last legs.
事已既成
It is what it is.
除了舌骨断裂和身体挫伤外
In addition to the fractured hyoid and the bruising,
我在他身上找到了挣扎过的痕迹
I got signs of a struggle around the body,
有几个目击者也认为 他们听到房里传来挣扎的声音
a couple of witnesses who thought they heard sounds of a struggle inside the house.
还有你减下来的那条丝带
Also that ribbon you snipped off,
好像跟另外几宗案子有关
it might tie to other cases.
那条丝带我们的调查员在现场都没看到
The ribbon my own investigator missed at the scene.
这种事很正常 丝带绑得很高
It happens. It was high on the wrist.
死因是勒颈谋杀
Cause and manner is homicide by strangulation.
大有收获啊 探长
Good hunting, Detective.
"如果有人对综合预算调节法案的福利待遇
"And anyone requiring additional information on COBRA benefits
"和退休金一次性支付的自愿离职计划有疑问
"and pension payout as part of the voluntary separation plan
"可以预约人力资源部门获取解答"
"can schedule an appointment with human resources."
有些人也许会调到其他职位
Some of you will migrate into new positions
其他人当然将会
while others will of course
离开太阳报另谋出路
be moving on to other opportunities beyond the Sun,
但在这房间中每个人的出色表现都有目共睹
but everyone in this room has done excellent work
你们该为自己所作出的贡献而感到骄傲
and should be proud of their contributions.
- 他们买断了多少人 - 还没决定
- How many buyouts are there? - That hasn't been determined yet.
我们今天晚点会跟工会讨论
We're talking to the union later today.
这对接下来跟同业协会的合同谈判会产生多大影响
How will this affect the upcoming contract negotiations with the guild?
影响极大 跟加薪说拜拜吧
Badly. Kiss any raise goodbye.
既然公司仍然盈利为什么新闻部还会裁员
How come there's cuts in the newsroom when the company's still profitable?
我此刻比你们更为光火
There's nobody that feels worse about this than I do.
大家在巴尔的摩的杰出表现我都看在眼里
I've seen the excellent work we've done here in Baltimore.
大家越快跟我们单独谈话
The sooner we start meeting with you individually,
你们的疑问才能越快得到解答
the sooner I can answer all of your questions.
不是O'Mara吧
Not O'Mara.
不妙
Aw, no.
祝你们好运啊 各位
Good luck, everybody.
重罪方面没有增加 总犯罪率增加1%
No increase in felonies and a 1% bump in total crime.
你敢担保这些数据的真实性吗
Do you vouch for these figures?
- 长官? - 我把你们预算减到最低 犯罪率也没有上升
- Sir? - No increase in crime even after I cut you guys to the bone.
你是想跟我说这个对吧
This is what you're telling me?
因为我对你们只有一个要求
Because the one thing I'm asking of you guys,
这个要求最为重要
the one thing that I'm asking above all,
就是你给我的数据不能作假
is that you bring me clean numbers.
当然 市长先生 你说的很清楚
Yes, Mr. Mayor. You made that clear.
很好
Very good, then.
Burrell气数已尽
Burrell is done.
他刚刚断送了自己的前途
He just killed himself.
我们公布真实数据留下掺水的 让他走得心甘情愿
We leak the real stats hold the cooked ones in case he won't go quietly.
然后把他换成谁 Rawls?
And replace him with who? Rawls?
他也带着同样的数字来的
He came in with the same stats.
以我对Bill Rawls的了解
If I know Bill Rawls, he'll be calling over here
他一回办公室就会打过来
as soon as he gets back to his office,
跟我说他已经警告过Burrell不要造假数据
telling us he warned Burrell against cooking the books.
部长们不会答应让Rawl上位的 Nerese也是
The ministers won't live with Rawls. Neither will Nerese.
如果只是做代理局长 他们会同意的 至少也会答应几个月
As acting commissioner, they will for a few months at least,
只要我们能推介给他们一位黑人候选者
if we've got a black candidate to sell them.
Daniels还不够格 他才当上警监一年
Daniels isn't ready. He's only been colonel for a year.
在这紧要关头 一年也就够了
A year will do in a pinch.
你把消息走漏给你在Calvert街上的伙计
You float it with one of your bunkies on Calvert Street.
探探风声
See how it plays.
Burrell要是知道了 会使坏的
Burrell reads that, he'll shit melons.
我倒是希望他闹事
I fucking hope so.
这里是巴尔的摩
It's Baltimore.
没有谁可以高枕无忧
No one lives forever.
Andreas 对吧
Andreas, right?
俄国佬让我来的
The Russian sent me.
请你给Vondas捎个话
Need you to get a word to Vondas.
就说他有了位新伙伴
He got a new friend.
我不知道你在说谁
I never hear the name.
就告诉他Marlo来过 还给他带了份大礼
Just let him know Marlo came past with a gift.
明天这个点我会再来
Be at you same time tomorrow.
谁知道要在这里等多久吗
Any idea how long this could take?
不晓得 可能一整天就耗这儿了
Don't know. Might be here all day.
我还有个会要开
I have meetings scheduled.
我们得踏踏实实的慢慢来
We've got to lay the foundation carefully,
这样大陪审团才能对每个上下庭的人心里有数
make it so the grand jurors understand all the ins and outs
不会被一堆细节搅得云里雾里
so they don't get lost in the details.
Howard先生
Mr. Howard?
有办法让我早点进去吗
Is there any way I could go earlier?
如果你身居要职 当然
If you're important enough, sure.
我是一个大型金融机构的副主席
I'm the vice president of a major financial institution.
谁他妈不是呢
Who the fuck isn't?
现在 先生 请注意您手中的文件
Now, sir, directing your attention to the document in your hand,
那是否也是一份财务报表
is that also an account statement?
是的 报表对象是一个非盈利组织的有息账户
Yes, it is, for a nonprofit, interest-bearing account,
标明属于美国免税非盈利组织中的第三类别
organizational, with 501 (c)3 designation.
你能以较慢的语速解释下
Can you begin by slowly explaining in the most basic terms
当中每一条
each of those things,
以非盈利开头的基本条款吗
beginning with the word nonprofit?
- 二号审讯室开了没 - 还没
- Hey, is box two open? - Not yet.
三号呢
What about three?
有人在杀流浪汉
Someone's killing homeless men.
法医都这么说
Medical examiner says so.
我这案子诡异得很呐 Bunk
Weird thing about my case, Bunk.
死掉的是个无家可归的流浪汉 但他手腕上
Dead man was homeless, but he had a red ribbon
系着条红丝带
tied around his wrist.
流浪汉有什么事要紧到
What does a homeless guy have to remember
他需要绑条红丝带来记住呢
that he should have a red ribbon tied around his wrist?
- Barlow - 咋了
- Barlow. - What?
污染空气啊
Nice out.
你以为你放的屁都跟香水似的吗  乡巴佬
Like Chanel No. 5 comes out of your ass, Moreland.
你的问题就是我的问题
If you got a problem, then I got a problem.
合作就是这么回事
That's how the co-op work.
遇到什么问题了
What's the problem?
我钱赚的太多
I got too much money.
小兄弟 相信我 不是就你有这烦恼
Son, believe me, you ain't alone.
跟我们东西怎么卖的没关系
What to do with the shit we sell ain't no thing.
在巴尔的摩 毒品供不应求好卖得很
In Baltimore, dope and coke sell themselves,
但赚回来的钱
but the money that come back?
多到床垫不够藏 是吧
Ain't enough mattresses, is there, now?
你有什么主意吗
You got any ideas?
有些门路 如果你需要的话
A few. If you askin'.
- 不是Twigg吧 - 该死
- Not Twigg. - Damn.
在报业埋头苦干20年 竟然得此下场
Guy gives 20 years to the paper, and this how it ends?
问题是 这年头出烂报纸挣小钱的
Fact of the matter is, it's more profitable these days
赚得还更多
to run a worse paper for less money.
裁员加上削减报纸版面 收入反而涨了
Cut back people and pages, you increase revenue.
如果咱们走运的话 他们该只裁掉些废物
If we're lucky, they'll just get rid of deadwood.
怎么样
How'd it go?
"你干得挺不错"
"You've done excellent work."
没说得太直白 他们让我做选择
Without being explicit, they gave me a choice
- 要么去编辑部 要么被买断辞退 - 开什么玩笑
- either the copy desk or the buyout. - You're kidding, right?
显然 他们留我在印刷部的钱
Apparently, they can hire 1.5 twentysomethings
够雇1.5个二十多岁小青年了 所以...
for what it costs to keep me in print, so...
见鬼 Roger
Damn, Roger.
我很遗憾 老兄
Sorry, man.
去他的 我还是去捣鼓那本美国巨著算了
Fuck it. I might as well get to work on that great American novel.
- 是我 - Gus 进来
- Yeah. - Gus, come on in.
请坐
Have a seat.
放心Gus 你对我们是必不可少的
Relax, Gus. We need you here.
我们很看重你的兢兢业业 你干得非常出色
We value your dedication. You've done excellent work.
我们还要靠你打造新的队伍
We're counting on you to transition the new team.
还会有很多才华洋溢的新人需要你栽培
There's still going to be excellent talent out there that needs to be developed.
旧队伍里还会剩下哪些人
What kind of team's going to be left?
我们损失了一些人才
We're losing good people,
但我们打算留下中流砥柱
but we expect to retain the core of a solid staff.
以小博大
Doing more with less.
这是我们必须得琢磨的前进之道
That's what we have to contemplate going forward.
以小博大是吧?
More with less, huh?
看看这
Look at this.
Ray Cole案件档案里的红丝带
A red ribbon in one of Ray Cole's files.
Cole还留了个字条  "在被害者左腕上发现"
Cole left a note with it. "Found on left wrist of victim.
"和其他案子相比对"
"Check against other cases."
嘿 亲爱的 柜子上那个污渍怎么样  干了没
Hey, hon. How's the stain look on the cabinets? They dry yet?
很好 我这就回来
Great. I'm on my way.
这才是麻烦的地方  要引起这些家伙的主意
This is the hard part, getting these guys to give a shit.
去喝一杯吧 我请
Let's get a taste. I'm buying.
你觉得我还会跟你把酒言欢
You think I'm drinking with you?
回家吧 Jimmy  再好好考虑下你干的混账事
Go home, Jimmy. Think your weak shit through, man.
回家?! 看在上帝的份上  我可是在查连环杀人犯
Go home? For the love of God, I'm working a serial killer.
你想谈谈吗
You want to talk on it?
上次跟Chris他们一起
Went with Chris and them,
去做掉一家子
set up on this family.
事已至此 非同小可
Everything so serious now.
呦 小鬼 你作业做完了吗
Yo, little man, you finish your homework?
现在天色已晚 如果我们还不回家就更晚了
'Cause it's late now, and it's only gonna get later if we don't roll home soon.
明天不用上学 教师会议
Ain't no school tomorrow. Teacher meetings.
我们该做点什么 Mike
We should do something, Mike.
我那片街头还要管 兄弟
Got my corner to run, man.
怎么了
What?
怎么了 小黑鬼
What, nigga?
六旗游乐园又重新开放了
Six Flags be open again.
搞什么等这么久
That shit's taking forever.
估计是什么复杂的事
Complicated stuff, I suppose.
肯定是Joe把事情搞得很复杂
It's more like Joe make it complicated.
这老家伙对谈话这码子事执着得很
That nigga got a thing for conversation.
不像Marlo
Not like Marlo.
跟他完全不同
Definitely not.
眼前这位牧师 就是为数不多的几个 我乐意把钱交给他的人之一
Now, see, pastor here, he one of about three I like to give money to.
帮他做点善事
Help with his good works and all that.
善事
Good works?
他在群岛上开展各式各样传教工作
He down with all kind of missionary work going on down in the islands.
帮别人建建教堂
You know, building a church for some folk,
修修校舍之类 搞的都是这种善举
a schoolhouse for some other folks, all kind of good shit like that.
你还建些什么
And what else y'all building?
- 医院 - 对 还有医院
- A hospital. - Hospital, yeah.
只不过他们开工开了十多年
Except they been building that mess for about ten years now,
根本就没完工过
and nothing ever actually get finished.
你用什么方法帮我洗钱
How you gonna clean my money?
我在岛上的银行开了很多账户
Got accounts at some of the banks down there.
捐款都是现金进
Donations come in as cash,
支票出
cashier's checks come out.
传票送不到加勒比群岛这种小地方
Tiny-ass Caribbean island don't truck with no subpoenas,
庭谕也一样 山高皇帝远
no court orders, none of that.
你付我总金额的一成
You pay ten on the dollar.
其他更多的就看你对那些需要帮助的人
Anything beyond that depends on your generosity,
愿意发多少善心了
to save those who want to be saved.
我回来了
I'm back.
看得出来
I can see that.
再来一杯
Again.
今天我看见你给我发的短信
I saw your text message on my cellphone today,
好一会儿才想起你他妈是谁
it took me a minute to remember who the hell you were.
也没过那么久吧
It ain't been that long.
去你的 你走的时候我还在报道劳工示威
Shit. When you left, I was still covering the labor beat.
咱们这里已经三年没有劳工记者了
We ain't had a labor reporter around here in three years.
你现在是油水横流的本地新闻总编
Yeah, well, now you the big, bad city editor,
我却跟妓女似的给政客典身卖命
and I'm whoring myself for politicians.
你走得正是时候
You got out just at the right time too.
- 情势这么糟糕么 - 芝加哥要逼死我们
- That bad, huh? - Chicago is killing us.
一次又一次收购
One buyout after another.
我简直无法想象下次同业协会谈判
I can't even begin to think what our next round of guild negotiations
会怎么样
is gonna be like.
我的叫苦连天就此打住
Enough of me crying.
你今晚有什么好料 亲爱的Norman
What are you selling tonight, dear Norman?
Carcetti计划除掉Burrell
Carcetti's planning to shitcan Burrell.
他在跟人交涉 考虑换掉他
He's talking to people and considering replacements.
市政厅传出来的消息?
City hall source?
谁是首要候选人
Who's the leading candidate?
Rawls 执行副局长 可能会接任几个月
Rawls, deputy for operations, might have the job for a few months,
不过还有位更名不见经传的卿点候选人
but there's a front runner from deeper In the department.
Cedric Daniels
Cedric Daniels.
我出来跑新闻也不是一年两年了 Norman
It's been a while since I've been on the street there, Norman.
- 这个Daniels是谁啊 - 刑侦部警监 根正苗红
- Who's this Daniels? - Chief of detectives. Polished.
有法律学位
Holds a law degree.
结了几宗高曝光率大案
Brought closure to some high-level cases.
他前妻上次还选上了市议员
His ex-wife got herself elected to the council last go-round.
我写的报道总是会附上照片
I always liked photos with my stories.
这次的目标又是谁
And this is aimed at who? Huh?
部长们? Nerese?
The ministers? Nerese?
你想看他们能不能接受这个家伙 对吧
You want to see if they can live with this fella here, right?
好吧
A'ight.
从一个卖笑的去找下一个
From one whore to another.
靠 搞什么鬼
Whoa, what the fuck?
看看这个
Check this shit out.
一片春光啊
Beautiful.
狗娘养的 看这混账
Holy shit. Look at this motherfucker.
打灯照他
Hit him with the spot.
刑侦部的 难怪
CID. Figures, don't it?
你们去哪儿
Where y'all need to go?
去六旗游乐场
Down Six Flags.
搭你往返
You talkin' round trip?
两百块加油费
Run you 200 plus gas.
你车在哪儿
Where you at?
一百五包含油费 如果这破烂开得到的话
I got 150, gas included if it even get us there.
别光看外表 这车可是经过千锤百炼
Don't be fretting on the ride now. This motherfucker tried and true.
好
A'ight.
到了那给你一半 回来再给你剩下的
I got half when we get there and half on the way back.
估计您老无心写报道了
I guess you're not up for a story.
- 我要你现在就开始着手写报道 - 你有什么消息
- I need something worked on right away. - What do you got?
市长想开除警察局长
Mayor's thinking about firing the police commissioner.
- 反正他在放这消息 - 没问题 交给我了
- He's floating the idea anyway. - No problem. I'm all over it.
你对Daniels有什么了解
What do you know about Daniels?
- 他是谁 - 刑侦部警监
- Who is he? - CID commander.
从东区缉毒署出来的
Came out of the Eastern DEU, married to the Daniels
曾跟06年赢得议员职位的Daniels是夫妻
that won the council seat in '06.
带来几个大型监听案 上头把西区给他管
Brought in a couple of big wiretap cases, they gave him the Western,
指望他在Bunny Colvin下台后 能给西区带来点起色
hoping to clean up that district after they shitcanned Bunny Colvin.
离婚后 他跟Ronnie Pearlman成了一对
Since getting separated, he's been shacked up with Ronnie Pearlman
她在州检察官办公室供职
over at the state's attorney's office.
在他职业生涯早期没遇上伯乐
No suction early in his career,
但现在有了Carcetti的提点
but now that he's got Carcetti's ear,
他前程一片光明
now the brass stay out of his way.
他最喜欢的颜色是啥
What's the man's favorite color?
- 你确定 - 对 管他呢
- You sure? - Yeah, what the hell?
反正我马上就要走人
I'm already on the clock.
嗨 亲爱的
Hi, darlin'.
我是太阳报的Roger Twigg
It's Roger Twigg with the Sun papers.
副局长在吗
Is the deputy around?
谢了 甜心
Thanks, hon.
给我一两个小时 我也会对他了如指掌
Hey, an hour or two, I'd have had it surrounded.
毫无疑问
No doubt.
在这位"废物"先生写报道的时候
While Mr. Deadwood here's working the story,
看你能不能帮他写点外界回应语录
see if you can feed him some react quotes.
的确是份厚礼
A generous gift,
但你的钱 你带给我的钱
but your money,the money you bring me.
我不需要
I don't need.
钱就是钱
Money is money.
谁带给你的又有什么关系
What's the difference who bring it to you?
这是不义之财
It's dirty money.
是臭钱
It stinks.
- 我们难道不是干同一行的 - 这些钱直接来自街头
- We ain't in the same business? - The bills are from the street.
是黑钱 你懂没
They're dirty, you understand?
所有交易都要经Joe之手
Everything runs through Joe.
Joe经手的 都是干净钱
Everything is clean with Joe.
没问题
Ain't a problem.
很好
Good.
再见
Goodbye.
Bunk 你说的那个红丝带上是打的哪种结
Hey, Bunk. What kind of knot you say was on that red ribbon?
- 就是绑在流浪汉手腕上的那个红丝带 - 你和你的红丝带都去死吧
- The one on the homeless guy's wrist. - Fuck yourself with your red ribbon.
刚想起件事
Just thought of something.
几个月前我有个流浪汉被杀的案子 流浪汉腕上绑着红丝带
I caught a vagrant months back had a red ribbon tied around his wrist.
你连这都记得
You remember that?
好个记性啊 探长 好个记性啊
Hell of a catch, Detective. Hell of a catch.
我能看你的案卷吗
Can I see your file?
干净的票子
Clean bills?
你是说洗干净是吧 就像我刚刚这样
You mean laundered, right? I just showed you how.
不不 他的意思是洗钱
Nah, nah. He mean clean,
能直接从银行进出的那种
like the money straight out the bank and shit.
看起来要是清白正当钱
All lookin' nice.
看吧 什么世道 你在这要付钱给这些个混球
See, people ain't right. Here you are tryin' to pay a motherfucker,
他居然尽担心钱看起来像什么样
an' all he worried about is what the money look like.
通常情况下 我要收两成的佣金
Normally, my fee for this would be 20 on the dollar.
给你四万当洗钱费
40,000 to make it look nice.
你还今天就要
You need this back today too.
一般收费更高
Might ordinarily charge more,
但看在我们合作的份上 免费
But seeing as how we co-op, no charge.
说到合作 跟你那些下手狠的黑鬼说
Speaking of co-op, tell them niggas that got burnt
我悬红5万给提供Omar和他手下消息的人
I'm givin' away 50 for a line on Omar's people.
他的姐妹 他的祖母 还有他的基友
His sister, his me-maw, some faggy he be with.
这些人都算 听见没
All that shit count, you hear me?
要是我就不会打草惊蛇 小子
I'd let sleeping dogs lie, son.
我知道你不会 Joe
I know you would, Joe.
你就是会耍伎俩
You smart like that.
我呢
Yeah. Me?
总之 把这悬红传出去
Anyway, pass that offer on.
一小时后回来取钱
Come back for this here in an hour.
那小子就想置Omar于死地
That boy want Omar bad.
我可什么Omar的消息都没供给他
Man, I ain't giving him a thing on Omar.
Omar已经走了
Omar been gone.
把他的恶史劣迹也一起带走了
Took a lot of bad history with him too.
我脑子坏掉才会盼这条恶狗再回来
Why in the hell would I want that motherfucker back?
你觉得我们刚坐的过山车有多快
How fast you think we were going on that first drop?
- 时速75千米吧 - 就这样?
- 75 an hour. - That's it?
感觉我都要从座位上飞出去了 哥们
Felt like I was coming out of my seat, man.
这些事情你咋都知道 怎么知道的
You always knowing stuff like that. How?
看那边
Over there!
你们都扔得太用力了
Y'all throwin' some bricks.
要轻轻的来
Put a little touch on it.
学着点
Watch.
给球加点下旋力 不然会弹出来
Put some backspin on it, or else it'll bank off the box and not in it.
拿着这个
Hold this.
- 那Fairfax在哪里 - 弗吉尼亚北部
- So where Fairfax at? - Northern Virginia.
- 你呢 - 我住在巴尔的摩
- How about you? - I live up Baltimore.
酷毙了
That's so cool.
你俩有自己的住处吗
You two have your own place?
- 是的 还有Bug - 关系真铁
- Yeah, and Bug. - That's tight.
有个疯子在逍遥法外是吧
Madman on the loose, huh?
已经有三起相关案子 而且可能还不止
Three linked cases and counting.
他在屠杀流浪汉是吧
He's killing vagrants, is he?
到时别说我没提醒你
Don't say I didn't warn you.
太阳报现在谁跟进咱们的案子 Twigg?
Who covers us for the Sun papers nowadays? Twigg?
是他或是新来的女孩儿 叫Alma什么的
Him or this new girl. Alma something.
巴尔的摩太阳报 我是Gutierrez
Baltimore Sun. Gutierrez.
好的 我能跟你面谈吗
OK. Can I meet you?
你知道阿尔帕西诺酒吧吗
Do you know Al Pacino's?
半个小时后见怎么样
How about half an hour?
好的 到那儿见
OK. See you then.
我这里拿到条挺好的回应  写在城市新闻版
Good react quote from me in Metro Write.
Scott 过来
Wow.Scott, come here.
这条回应
This quote here -
"Carcetti将要痛下杀招 Daniels助他磨刀霍霍
"Carcetti may be holding the knife, but Daniels sharpened it for him.
选举之后他就对Burrell百般挑剔"
He's been critical of Burrell since the election."
精辟 对吧
Good shit, huh?
对 来自市政厅的高级官员
Yeah, from a high-ranking city hall source?
你介意告诉我从哪得来的消息吗
You feel comfortable telling me where you got that?
不行 是我的线人
Not really, it being a source.
是条绝佳的语录  不过如果你想匿名扇人家耳光
It's a great quote, but if you're gonna slam somebody anonymously,
至少我得知道这条回应从何而来
I at least have to be sure that the quote comes from...
Nerese Campbell
Nerese Campbell.
她不会公开对市长的选择出言不逊
She's not gonna slam the mayor's choice publicly
但在不透露信息来源的条件下  那是她的回应
but not-for-attribution, that's her quote.
你让Nerese说出了这话 是吧
You got Nerese to say that, huh?
不是只有Twigg是这里的弄潮儿
Twigg's not the only guy who's game around here.
告诉Vondas我之前不是有意造成误会
Let Vondas know I ain't mean no misunderstanding earlier.
你怎么知道这几个案子有关联的
How do you know they're connected?
是有DNA证据 还是有惯用作案手法
Is there DNA evidence or a signature?
这个我们不能公布 你知道  为了避免有模仿者
We can't release that yet. You know, copycats.
所以的确是有惯用手法
So there is a signature.
怎么了
What?
你挺厉害
You're good.
- 你是新人 对吧 - 才来五个月
- You're new, right? - Five months.
在此之前我在劳德代尔堡的太阳哨兵报工作
I worked at the Sun-Sentinel in Lauderdale before this.
我读过你的报道 很不错
I've read your stories. They're good.
胡说 但还是谢谢
Bullshit, but thanks.
你会马上出第一手报道对不对
You're gonna run something right away, right?
这一点我必须得到你的确认
We got to get the word out on this.
Alma算哪门子名字啊
What kind of name is Alma?
我有男友 探长
I have a boyfriend, Detective.
是吗 他大得过我么
Yeah? He bigger than me?
我能请问为何在我们提及的这天  当你开着参议院的车
Can I ask you why on the day in question  you were operating the senator's car
被市警羁押时 身上带着两万块现金吗
when you were detained by city police  with $20,000 in cash?
经我律师建议 我不能回答这个问题
On advice of my attorney, I ain't gonna answer that.
你们都想在这儿定我的罪
Y'all trying to criminate me here.
Price先生 你作为司机受雇于Davis参议员
Mr. Price, you are employed as a driver for Senator Davis,
年收入三万块 对不对
earning 30,000 a year, is that correct?
对 那又怎么样
Yeah, so?
不过我也了解到
Yet it is my understanding
你同时兼任巴尔的摩西区篮球
that you are also drawing a $40,000 salary
慈善执行总监年收入四万块
as the executive director of the West Baltimore hoops charity
还兼任参议员日托提案的筹款总监
and another 30,000 as the fundraising director
年收三万块
for the senator's day-care initiative.
你怎么能同时兼顾三份工作
How are you able to earn three salaries,
赚三份薪水呢 Price先生
working three jobs at the same time, Mr. Price?
祝你有个愉快的一天
You have a nice day.
老瞎鬼
Blind motherfucker.
他的酒馆开在 Collington街东面
His joint on Collington on the east side of the street.
如果他招出Omar 算账时加我一个
If he give up Omar, though, I want in on that shit.
死黑鬼拿枪指过我的头
Nigga put a gun in my face, man.
- Joe知道Butchie这人吗 - 他妈的 是我认识他
- Joe know about Butchie? - Motherfucker, I know about him.
Joe完全不知道这码子事 他也不用知道
Joe don't know shit about this here, and he ain't need to know.
现在我的赏金呢
Now where my cheese at, man?
你他妈的死去哪儿了 黑仔
The fuck you been at, nigga?
今天不用上学 所以我们带Bug出去了 没什么的吧
Wasn't no school today, so we took Bug to do something. Ain't no thing.
你谁都不打个招呼就要紧
It is when you don't tell no one.
搞得我今天在这里守一天  确保你的人没乱来
Now I had to come down her all day long  to make sure your shit is straight.
这还是你的地盘不 黑仔
This your corner or what, nigga?
我这不结束的时候过来检查今天的成果了吗
I'm checking now to make sure shit's right at the end of the day,
够了不
a'ight?
- 数目对不 - 都对得上
- Yo, count right? - Yeah. All straight.
这不是重点 你也知道  Chris已经收到消息了
Ain't the point, and you know it. Chris already heard about this shit.
海豚不错 黑仔
- Nice dolphin, nigga. - hmm.
回家吧 哥们 我下次再来料理这烂摊子
Let's go home, man. I'll deal with this bullshit later.
这是你在群岛的银行账户上存的40万
That's 400 in your own account down in the islands.
飓风 司法部
There no hurricane, department of justice,
操着枪的黑鬼都动不到它一分一毫
or nigga with a gun can tap that.
- 我怎么知道钱都在那儿 - 你随时可以上网查看
- How I even know it's there? -You check it online any time you like.
在电脑上?
On a computer?
最好是能亲手摸到
If I can't hold it in my hand...
好吧 你有没有前科
A'ight. You got any prior convictions?
没有 没有记录在案的
No, nothing that rate.
那我们给你弄个护照
We get you a passport, then.
去趟旅行
Take a trip.
这家伙真他妈食古不化
Ain't easy civilizing this motherfucker.
我们没什么选择的余地 Gus
We chose poorly, Gus.
是啊
Yeah.
这样下去 10年后不会有啥像样的报纸了
At this rate, there won't be much to call a newspaper in 10 years.
你知道我父亲在阿姆科钢铁工作对吧
You know my father worked over at Armco, right?
他每天早晨上工前
And every morning before he went to work,
都坐在桌边 喝着咖啡看报纸
he'd sit at the table, reading the newspaper with a cup of coffee,
旁若无人
and no one could interrupt him
出门前那十五分钟都是如此
for that 15 minutes before he walked out the door.
我还记得当时看着他 就想着
And I remember watching him, thinking,
"那张破报纸有什么非看不可的
"What the hell is so important about that damn paper?
"我也想成为那里面的一部分"
"I want to be part of that."
让我就此想当新闻工作者
Made me want to be a newspaperman.
有一天 我旷课在Patterson闲晃
One day, I was cutting class at Patterson,
在去市中心的巴士上有个男的
and there was this man on the downtown bus
把报纸叠得方方正正
folding his broadsheet just so.
那哥们叠报纸的方式
And the way that man folded that paper
和他看报纸时聚精会神的样子
and concentrated on reading those pages
让他一眼看去就是巴士上最聪明的家伙
made him look like the smartest son of a bitch on the bus.
就是那种惊鸿一瞥的瞬间
It was just one of those moments.
美国文学家门肯的墓志铭
"有朝一日 若我已辞世
"Lf, ever I depart this vale,
"你若忆起我
"and you ever remember me
"仍意于取悦我的鬼魂
"and have thought to please my ghost,
"那就宽恕戴罪之人
"forgive some sinner,
"追求貌平之女"
"and wink your eye at some homely girl."
让亨利·门肯见鬼去吧
Fuck Henry Mencken.
我原谅你了 Gus
I forgive you, Gus.
市长考虑变动警局局长之职
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
你看见那条引述某人说的 我背后捅了Burrell一刀的话了吗
You see that quote from somebody about me  stabbing Burrell in the back?
完全是鬼话连篇
That's a damn lie.
那又怎样
So what?
你会被提名为局长
You're going to be named commissioner.
这是好消息啊 哪里不好了
This is good news. How is this not good news?
谢谢
Thanks.
拿去吧 穷鬼
Cheap motherfucker.
市长考虑变动警局局长之职
流浪者被杀案似有关联
不对不对 看见没
No, no, see.
如果你跟本地啤酒放在一起
If you stack it with the domestic beer,
我不是就分不出来了吗
then I won't know, huh?
给瞎子行个方便吧 听见没
Cut a blind man some slack, hear?
- 你们开业没 - 如果你带了身份证的话
- Y'all servin'? - If you got some ID on you.
- 是谁啊 - 小女孩
- Who was that? - Little girl.
现金放在收银台
Cash is in the register.
去他的收银台 老家伙
Fuck the register, old man.
他们都在抓你把柄
They all up in your shit.
他们什么陈芝麻烂谷子都在查 你听见了吗
They going after every damn thing. Do you hear me?
我们要坐牢了
We going to jail.
注意点 狗杂种
Focus, motherfucker,
注意点
focus!
瞧这里
Look here.
在腰带广告背后 就在...
Back in the girdle ads underneath the story about the...
校董会通过114公立学校改名的新闻下面
the school board approving a name change for PS 114,
就是咱Jimmy McNulty的杀人魔报道
it's Jimmy McNulty's ripper.
你知道他们为什么被叫做流浪汉吗 Jimmy
You know why they call them homeless, Jimmy?
因为他们连个尿尿的便壶都没有
Because they ain't got a pot to piss in,
你知道为啥他们连个尿尿的便壶都没有吗
and you know why they ain't got a pot?
因为谁他妈都不在乎
Because nobody gives a good fuck.
你闹个一两天就该给我收手回去轮班
Shake it for another day or two, and then you're back in the rotation.
你蠢事干够了没
You done with this stupid shit?
还要谁来当头棒喝才能敲醒你 Jimmy
Who the fuck do you need to hear it from, Jimmy?
你得让Burrell知道这不是你本意
You have to let Burrell know that this isn't coming from you.
那根本没用
That won't matter.
今天他看过这个之后 我就是眼中钉
After what he read today, I'm the threat.
那你必须告诉他你不会接这个工作
Then you have to tell him that you won't take the job,
你并不觊觎他的位置
that you don't want his chair.
他会信我吗
And he believes me?
要不然他就会把他知道的公之于众
The alternative is that  he goes public with what he knows,
把你的老底掀出来
whatever he has about the old days.
他都藏了这么久了
He sat on it this long.
你自己也说过 比起让外界知道 在他掌管下警局的家丑
You said yourself he'd rather bury that file
还不如把这段陈年旧事尘封起来
than to embarrass the department on his watch,
但如果是你跟他两虎相争
but if it's between you and him surviving,
你觉得他会怎么做
what do you think he'll do then?
那份档案里到底会有多少料
How much could even be in that file?
资产调查和一些闲言闲语?
An assets investigation? Some loose talk?
都多久以前的事了  当年那些人都罢手了
It was so long ago. Most of those guys have moved on.
他只用放出点风声
He only needs smoke.
甚至不用煽风点火 就能拖你下台
He doesn't even need fire to drag you down, to drag me down.
把我们多年的苦心经营毁于一旦
Everything that we have worked so hard for.
我们已经失去得够多了
We've already lost enough.
Omar还有些什么手下
What other people Omar got?
他才是我们要算账的
Cocksucker the one got the trouble.
你没必要为他送命
No need for you to stand tall on it.
不用把场子搞这么难堪
It don't have to be messy.
没别的办法 我看得出来
Ain't no other way. I can see that.
我在哪儿才能找到Omar
Where I find Omar?
不 不
no,no...
Omar在哪儿
Where Omar at?
老家伙是条硬汉
You a tough old man.
消息传到Omar的时候  记得要事无巨细的说给他听
When word get to Omar, make sure he hear everything.
我们还是没有Omar的消息  现在他还要找上门了
We still ain't got no line on the man, and now he comin' at us.
我们要变动下 Marlo以后少出门
We gonna change up. Marlo got to move indoors.
咱们得提心吊胆过日子了
The rest of us need to live on the run.
要我说 这计划烂毙了
Fucked-up plan, you ask me.
Marlo要Omar死 你知道这个就够了
Marlo wants Omar. What else you need to know?
你要下手除掉Burrell 我不怪你
You making your move on Burrell, and I don't blame you,
而且事实上 也没有我插手的余地
and the thing is, I can help with that.
部长们 Nerese 黑人立法协会
The ministers, Nerese, black legislative caucus
我能把他们都找来
I can bring them around for you.
随意
Feel free.
我只求在大陪审团这操蛋事上帮我点忙
All I need is some help with this grand jury nonsense.
你去找Bond 你去跟Bond说
You go to Bond, you tell Bond that...
这事我帮不了你
I can't help you with that.
消息已经满天飞了  我们的电话也没响
Story's been out all day, and our phone isn't ringing.
部长 Nerese 黑人立法协会 显然他们可以接受Daniels
The ministers, Nerese, the caucus, they're willing to live with Daniels apparently.
还是谢谢你
Thanks anyway.
你自以为可以甩掉Clay了是不
Thinking you can cut Clay loose, huh?
觉得我玩儿完了
Thinking I'm done.
西印度群岛人民银行
你好
我来看我的账户
Came to see my account.
(法语)您不会说法语吗
里面有我的钱吗
Y'all got my money in here?
(法语)我不会说英语
这是我的 你们这儿有我的钱
This mine. Y'all got my money.
(法语)是的 先生
we missed you.
(法语)我想看一下
(法语)请把那个从这边递过来 就这边
(法语)谢谢
- (法语)请出示证件 - 什么
- What?
- (法语)这个 - 是的
- Yeah.
(法语)对了
(法语)多谢
好的 Marlo先生
所以你把Barlow那宗谋杀案
So you string together Barlow's murder
和Cole的和你的无关案子扯上关系
and Cole's unconnected case and yours,
这样就能自然而然的开展调查...
which is natural to begin with...
即兴连环杀手  我本以为会逼Brass
Instant serial killer, which I thought would get the brass
扔点钱出来让我们查真正的案子
to begin kicking out some money  to work real cases.
- 好比Marlo - 好比Marlo
- Like Marlo? - Like Marlo.
你脑子里居然还装着这种鸟想法
Shit like this actually goes through your fucking brain?
是啊 如果你不听老搭档的
Yeah. If you don't want to listen to your partner,
听听Lester的怎么说 他够聪明了吧
then listen to Lester. He has all the wisdom you need.
可笑的是 根本没在在乎连环杀手
Joke of it is, no one gives a fuck about a serial killer,
只要他杀的不是学生什么的
not unless he's carving up some pretty coed or some shit.
太阳报把这新闻放在尾页上
Sun papers put the story in their back pages.
- 你搞砸了 - 对 跟他说
- You fucked up. - Yeah. Tell him.
不 我是说 如果你真想成事儿的话 一个简单的扼杀案根本不够
No. I mean, if you want to do it right, a straight-up strangle's not enough.
在死的只是流浪汉的情况下
Not if it's some vagrant.
把这事夸大
Sensationalize it.
给杀手安个什么妄想症的名头
Give the killer some fucked-up fantasy,
要极为变态 令人发指的那种
something bad, real bad.
要能紧抓住观者的胃口
It's got to grip the hearts and minds,
打造个他们想看到的连环杀手
give the people what they want from a serial killer.
- Lester 你搞什么 - 不 你这事有戏
- Lester, what the fuck? - No. You're onto something.
我再需几个礼拜 就能把Marlo Stanfield逮捕归案
I only need a few weeks to pull down Marlo Stanfield.
你别把这事搞砸 就能给我那几个礼拜
You fly this mess right, you can give it to me.
谁会在乎我们捏造几个
Who gives a damn  if we fake a couple of murders
本来就破不了的谋杀案
that we're never gonna solve, huh?
死人不在乎
The dead men don't care.
没人在乎
No one cares.
但如果能让上头拿几个钱出来查案
But if it's gonna get the bosses  to throw down enough coin to do police work...
我走了 我待不下去了
I'm out. I'm out of here.
我们得给你的连环杀手想个名号
We got to give your killer a name.
我们必须再犯次案
We have to kill again.
老兄 总有一天我们得把这个弄来吃
Poppy, we've got to cook  one of these one night.
- 说的是 - 弄顿美味的晚餐
- Yeah, right on. - Nice little dinner.
Omar  Omar  Omar
Omar, Omar, Omar!
慢慢来 慢慢来 别急 别急
Hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on.
好吧 好吧 拿去
All right, all right. Here you go.
Mana 明天再来 好不好
Tomorrow, OK?
- 明天 - Mana Poppy
- Tomorrow. - Mana Poppy
Mana Alexis
嘿 Naldo 你兄弟得找找 哪儿有卖蜂蜜燕麦圈的
Hey, 'Naldo, cous' got to find out where they got Honey Nut, yo,
如果他指望我们把这鸟大的地方当家的话
if they expect us to call this spit o' land home.
(西语)我接到个电话
(西语)有个坏消息
(西语)出了什么事
(西语)他们杀了Butchie